Lindsey Lauria

Address Irvine, CA 92603 Phone 714-552-9511 Email ljjlauria@mac.com **LinkedIn** https://www.linkedin.com/in/lindseyjjlauria **GitHub** https://github.com/LindseyJeeJan **Website** http://www.jeejan.com

Summary

Over 14 years of experience working with cross functional stakeholders to design and develop responsive and accessible user interfaces. Eight years experience developing front end of large scale web based application.

Technical Skills

Wireframing, rapid prototyping, accessibility, interaction design, Sketch, Photoshop, Agile, JIRA, Git, HTML5, CSS3, LESS, Browserstack, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, Web APIs, RESTful APIs, web forms, form validation.

Projects

Interactive Quiz

Single page application consisting of a timed quiz for the user developed with JavaScript.

URL https://github.com/LindseyJeeJan/interactive-code-quiz

Deployed Project https://

lindseyjeejan.github.io/interactive-code-quiz/

Work Day Scheduler

Simple calendar application that allows a user to save events for each hour of the day. Uses Bootstrap and Font Awesome and jQuery.

URL https://github.com/LindseyJeeJan/calendar-scheduler

Deployed Project https:// lindseyjeejan.github.io/calendar-scheduler/

Experience

Interaction Designer • Ultimate Kronos Group, Incorporated • Irvine, CA • 05/2012 ~ Current

- Designed features in Sketch, produced wireframes, clickable prototypes and multiple deliverable formats for use across organization. Lead design presentations to clearly articulate concepts to technical and non-technical audiences.
- Participated in continuous collaboration with programmers, Product Managers and stakeholders
 to provide technical guidance for best practices on front end architecture. Reviewed technical
 considerations along with business requirements to recommend how to achieve a successful
 design within the time budget.
- Created and maintained visual design system while producing a large volume of reusable design components and responsive full page layouts, coded by hand in HTML5 and CSS3.
- Continuously reviewed potential application improvements to ensure technology is utilizing the latest browser supported features. Performed iterative front end design reviews ensure development is completed on time and prevent costly code fixes.
- Solved cross platform and cross browser issues to maximize acceptance across supported platforms and browsers, performed cross browser testing in BrowserStack.

 Lead, defined and implemented accessibility standards initiative through the translation of WAI-ARIA accessibility standards into technical tasks to conform to a WCAG 2.0 AA acceptance criteria.

Web Developer • Glidewell Laboratories • Newport Beach, CA • 08/2006 ~ 05/2012

- Created and maintained corporate websites using search engine optimization and implementation of Google Analytics to measure traffic and visitor trends. Used Photoshop to extract digital print graphics and turn them into interactive, media rich websites with Adobe Flash.
- Developed front end of customer facing application along side team of programmers for an ASP.NET application using Microsoft TFS.

Education

California Polytechnic State University • San Luis Obispo, CA • 1997 ~ 2001 Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, concentration in Management Information Systems.

UCI Division of Continuing Education • Irvine, CA Certificate, Full Stack Flex Program

Department of Homeland Security Office of Accessible Systems & Technology Certificate, Trusted Tester